<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Yibin Lin's Reading Blog</title><link>https://yibinlin.github.io/readings/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Yibin Lin's Reading Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yibinlin.github.io/readings/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Python Study</title><link>https://yibinlin.github.io/readings/posts/python_study/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yibinlin.github.io/readings/posts/python_study/</guid><description>Python Type Projects A type object = an instance of type class = a normal class type and class are interchangable since Python 2.4 print(type(type)) # result: &amp;lt;class 'type'&amp;gt; print(type(str)) # result: &amp;lt;class 'type'&amp;gt; So type class is also an instance of type class. This is basica building block of Python, and cannot be expressed in Python language. In python everything is an object, so a class is an object (instance) of type.</description></item><item><title>Crypto Notes</title><link>https://yibinlin.github.io/readings/posts/crypto_notes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yibinlin.github.io/readings/posts/crypto_notes/</guid><description>BlockChain Scalability problems Nice Summary on Wikipedia E.g. Bitcoin can only process around 7 transactions (tx) / sec. Limited by block size Hard fork like Bitcoin cash to increase the block size. Soft fork like Seg Wit (both old and new nodes can still run on the same blockchain) &amp;ldquo;Layer 2&amp;rdquo; systems like Lightning Network creates channel on the worker nodes to send payments if users don&amp;rsquo;t follow the channel payment, penalty is that the payment will be lost.</description></item><item><title>Mac OS Setup</title><link>https://yibinlin.github.io/readings/posts/mac_os_setup/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yibinlin.github.io/readings/posts/mac_os_setup/</guid><description>Setting up vim &amp;#34; You need to import default vim settings first, e.g. syntax highlighting, etc.source $VIMRUNTIME/defaults.vi&amp;#34; Set non visual mode when mouse is dragging on vimset mouse-=a&amp;#34; set 1 tab == 4 spaces..filetype plugin indent on&amp;#34; show existing tab with 4 spaces widthset tabstop=4&amp;#34; when indenting with &amp;#39;&amp;gt;&amp;#39;, use 4 spaces widthset shiftwidth=4&amp;#34; On pressing tab, insert 4 spacesset expandtabrun .bashrc at .bash_profile time if [ -f $HOME/.bashrc ]; then source $HOME/.</description></item><item><title>Airflow Study Notes</title><link>https://yibinlin.github.io/readings/posts/airflow_notes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yibinlin.github.io/readings/posts/airflow_notes/</guid><description>1. Environment Vagrant: create and configure lightweight, reproducible dev environments (local Kubernetes cluster) 2.1 Basics 2.1.1 Concepts Operator: describes a single task in your data pipeline. Task: an instance of an operator Workflow: everything defined in Airflow. Architecture 2.2 Installation Using docker Docker mysterious image tags, e.g. slim, buster, etc. buster is Debian release names, makes sense.. Alpine Linux is a distro: The Alpine Docker image is extremely popular as it is only 5.</description></item><item><title>Notes on CSS</title><link>https://yibinlin.github.io/readings/posts/css_notes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yibinlin.github.io/readings/posts/css_notes/</guid><description>General Guideline Try to re-build layout of other websites, as practice, etc. Flexbox Flexbox cheat sheet justify-content means alignment in the main axis. align-items means alignment in the cross axis. Difference between Flex and Grid: Flex is 1-dimensional (and one direction), while grid is for 2-dimensional formatting. BEM Naming Convention BEM cheat sheet RSCSS vs. BEM Grids Grids can overlap if it is explicitly set.</description></item></channel></rss>